Guide to the Lars Onsager Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- RESEARCH MATERIAL, [pre-1930?]-1976; Series II; 4 linear feet (10 boxes)
  - Mathematics
    - "Laplace +"/TS, "Note on the Product Expansion of Theta Functions"/TS, "The Distribution of Energy in Turbulence" (no. 25)/MS, "Asymptotic Formula for # o(x, y)"/MS, "Relaxation Matrices" (Box 12, Folder 162, Reel 8)
    - "Info[rmation] Cascade"/canonical distribution with two-body forces; combinatorics; #f log f-SM (Box 12, Folder 163, Reel 8)
    - "Multiple Electron Scattering" (Box 12, Folder 164, Reel 8)
    - Notebook/eigenvalue problems-SM/eigenvalue problem by continued fractions-SM/Mathieu functions of index ½-SM/"Two-dimensional Green function" (Box 12, Folder 165, Reel 8)
    - "Reflex Waves" (Box 12, Folder 166, Reel 8)
    - "Milne Problem (2 dim[ensional]) Example of # scattering" (Box 12, Folder 167, Reel 8)
    - "Spectroscopy. Information and Article Abstract"/ "Literature review, by whom?"-PAL/"Slater's directed bonding theory"/"electron configuration of CH 2" (Box 12, Folder 168, Reel 8)
    - "Bounds for |F#/F|"/f#³(x)=p(x)f(x) (Box 12, Folder 169, Reel 8)
    - "Fragment re Waves"/wave equation with absorption-SM (Box 12, Folder 170, Reel 8)
    - "Waves"/Jeans/MS, "A. Conditions of existence. Let a physical phenomenon be described by a wave of amplitude n(x,t) propagating in the x direction…. B. Condition of Reality…. C. Condition of Causation…. D.Definition of σ(ν) for complex ν …. E. Interpretation ofσ(μ)…." (Box 12, Folder 171, Reel 8)
    - "Lagrange Interpretation-Multiple Points"/MS, "Given function f(z) and analytic in domain. Appropriate by polynomial p(z) such that p(z)=f(z); z=¾ 1,… ¾ n…." (Box 12, Folder 172, Reel 8)
    - "Spheroidal Harmonics" (Box 12, Folder 173, Reel 8)
    - "Population"/y 1+Y 2+Y 3=P; Y 1Y 2+Y 2Y 3+Y 3Y 1=g; Y 1Y 2Y 3=r (Box 12, Folder 174, Reel 8)
    - "Orthogonal Op[erator]s" (Box 13, Folder 175, Reel 8)
    - "Yang" (Box 13, Folder 176, Reel 9)
    - "Elliptic"/contour integration-SM (Box 13, Folder 177, Reel 9)
    - "Î¶(Î´)"/Î¸3 (2|Ï„)=(-iÏ„)-Â½e (z^2/Ï€iÏ„)Î¸3(-2/Ï„|-1/Ï„) (Box 13, Folder 178, Reel 9)
    - "se s=#" (Box 13, Folder 179, Reel 9)
    - "Î"âˆž" (infinite determinants) (Box 13, Folder 180, Reel 9)
    - "Toplitz Matrices" (Box 13, Folder 181, Reel 9)
    - "Kubo + heat exch[an]ge function µ(x;y)"/MS (Box 13, Folder 182, Reel 9)
    - "Serpentine"/antigorite, chrysotile/"L.O. wanted to use it for superleaks for liquid He"-SM/memo, "The Structure of Chrysotile Asbestos," 1953 (Box 13, Folder 183, Reel 9)
    - "S.C. Green's Functions"/"Singularities of Joyce's f.c.c. solution" (Box 13, Folder 184, Reel 9)
    - "d n2k/3" (Box 13, Folder 185, Reel 9)
    - "I 3"/contour integrations; body-centered cubic; errors in lifetime computations-SM (Box 13, Folder 186, Reel 9)
    - Unidentified (Box 13, Folder 187, Reel 9)
    - "Asymptotic Expansions of Whitaker Functions"/MS, "Improved Asymptotic Expansions" (Box 13, Folder 188, Reel 9)
  - Unclassified
    - Unidentified/ca. 1963-1972? (Box 13, Folder 189, Reel 9)
    - "Wood Porosity" (Box 13, Folder 190, Reel 9)
    - Unidentified/1970 (Box 13, Folder 191, Reel 9)
    - Unidentified (Box 13, Folder 192-193, Reel 9)
    - M. Brown and E.G. Murphy, "Measurements of the Self-Diffusion Coefficient of Uranium Hexafluoride" (Box 13, Folder 194, Reel 9)
    - Unidentified (Box 13, Folder 195, Reel 9)
    - Conference on "Basic Mechanisms in Radiobiology" at Brookhaven National Laboratory, 1953 May 7-9/MS, "For that matter, recent kinetic studies have revealed (Eigen, 1967) that replacements in the innermost shell of solvent molecules and anions around a cation may be fairly infrequent…." (Box 13, Folder 196, Reel 9)
    - Unidentified/C. Jaccard, "Thermodynamics of Irreversible Processes Applied to Ice," Physik der Kondensierten Materie 3, 99-118 (1964) (Box 13, Folder 197, Reel 9)
    - Unidentified/1976 (Box 13, Folder 198, Reel 9)
    - Unidentified/1975 Dec (Box 13, Folder 199, Reel 9)
    - Unidentified/post-1970 Jan (Box 13, Folder 200, Reel 9)
    - Unidentified (Box 13, Folder 201, Reel 9)
    - Unidentified/1974? (Box 13, Folder 202, Reel 9)
    - Unidentified/"Image Force"/1973? (Box 14, Folder 203, Reel 9)
    - "Protons, Miscell."/A. Draegert (Box 14, Folder 204, Reel 9)
    - Unidentified (Box 14, Folder 205-207, Reel 9)
    - Unidentified/1976 (Box 14, Folder 208, Reel 9)
    - Unidentified/post-1972? (Box 14, Folder 209, Reel 9)
    - Unidentified (Box 14, Folder 210-213, Reel 9)
    - "Computations" (Box 14, Folder 214, Reel 9)
    - Unidentified (Box 14, Folder 215-216, Reel 9)
    - Unidentified transparencies (Box 14, Folder 217, Reel 9)
    - Unidentified (Box 14, Folder 218, Reel 9)
    - Unidentified/S.N. Bagchi, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 219, Reel 9)
    - Unidentified/1967-1971 (Box 14, Folder 220, Reel 9)
    - Unidentified (Box 14, Folder 221, Reel 9)
    - "H 3IO 6"-SM (Box 14, Folder 222, Reel 9)
    - Unidentified (Box 14, Folder 223, Reel 9)
    - Unidentified/1951, 1954 (Box 14, Folder 224, Reel 9)
    - Unidentified/J.L. Lebowitz and E.H. Lieb, "Existence of Thermodynamics for Real Matter with Coulomb Forces" (Box 14, Folder 225, Reel 9)
    - "Figures (MS)" (Box 14, Folder 226, Reel 9)
    - Unidentified (Box 14, Folder 227, Reel 9)
- WRITINGS, 1926-1977; Series III; 1.25 linear feet (3 boxes)
  This series is divided into three sections: Publications, Pre-Publication Material, and Lecture Series. In the first two sections, the titles are arranged and numbered to follow the bibliography published by the Royal Society, a copy of which is in folder 1. Items not in the bibliography appear at the end of the appropriate section. Lecture Series is in chronological order.
  - Publications
    - Published bibliography (Biographical Memoirs of Fellows of the Royal Society, 24 [1978], 467-70) (Box 15, Folder 1, Reel 10)
    - Manuscript bibliographies, 1962-1966 (Box 15, Folder 2, Reel 10)
    - 1. Zur Theorie der Electrolyte, I (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel 10)
    - 2. Zur Theorie der Electrolyte, II (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel 10)
    - 3. Report on a revision of the conductivity theory (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel 10)
    - 4. Activity coefficients and mass-action law in electrolytes (Box 15, Folder 6, Reel 10)
    - 5. Simultane irreversible Processer (Box 15, Folder 7, Reel 10)
    - 6. Reciprocal relations in irreversible processes. I (Box 15, Folder 8, Reel 10)
    - 7. Reciprocal relations in irreversible processes. II (Box 15, Folder 9, Reel 10)
    - 8. Irreversible processes in electrolytes (Box 15, Folder 10, Reel 10)
    - 9. Viscosity and particle shape in colloid solutions (Box 15, Folder 11, Reel 10)
    - 10. Theories of concentrated electrolytes (Box 15, Folder 12, Reel 10)
    - 11. The surface tension of Debye-Hückel electrolytes (Box 15, Folder 13, Reel 10)
    - 12. Deviations from Ohm's law in weak electrolytes (Box 15, Folder 14, Reel 10)
    - 14. Electric moments of molecules in liquids (Box 15, Folder 15, Reel 10)
    - 15. Initial recombination of ions (Box 15, Folder 16, Reel 10)
    - 16. Electrostatic interaction of molecules (Box 15, Folder 17, Reel 10)
    - 17. On the theory of isotope separation by thermal diffusion (Box 15, Folder 18, Reel 10)
    - 18. Separation of gas (isotope) mixtures by irreversible processes (Box 15, Folder 19, Reel 10)
    - 19. Turbulence in convection gases between concentric vertical cylinders (Box 15, Folder 20, Reel 10)
    - 20. Separation of isotopes by thermal diffusion (Box 15, Folder 21, Reel 10)
    - 21. Anisotropic solutions of colloids (Box 15, Folder 22, Reel 10)
    - 22. Crystal statistics (Box 15, Folder 23, Reel 10)
    - 23. Crystal statistics. I. A two-dimensional model with an order-disorder transition (Box 15, Folder 24, Reel 10)
    - 24. Theories and problems of liquid diffusion (Box 15, Folder 25, Reel 10)
    - 25. The distribution of energy in turbulence (Box 15, Folder 26, Reel 10)
    - 26. Transition points (Box 15, Folder 27, Reel 10)
    - 27. De Haas-van Alphen effect in zinc (Box 15, Folder 28, Reel 10)
    - 28. Effects of shape on the interaction of colloidal particles (Box 15, Folder 29, Reel 10)
    - 29. Crystal statistics. III. Short-range order in a binary Ising lattice (also B. Kaufman. Crystal statistics. II) (Box 15, Folder 30, Reel 10)
    - 30. Statistical hydrodynamics (Box 15, Folder 31, Reel 10)
    - 31. Apparatus for isotope separation by thermal diffusion (Box 15, Folder 32, Reel 10)
    - 32. Interpretation of the de Haas-van Alphen effect (Box 15, Folder 33, Reel 10)
    - 33. General theory for the Guoy diffusion method (Box 15, Folder 34, Reel 10)
    - 34. Fluctuations and irreversible processes (Box 15, Folder 35, Reel 10)
    - 35. Fluctuations and irreversible process. II. Systems with kinetic energy (Box 15, Folder 36, Reel 10)
    - 36. Diamagnetism in metals (Box 15, Folder 37, Reel 10)
    - 37. Introductory talk (on liquid helium) (Box 15, Folder 38, Reel 10)
    - 38. Conductance of strong electrolytes at finite dilutions (Box 15, Folder 39, Reel 10)
    - 39. Bose-Einstein condensation and liquid helium (Box 15, Folder 40, Reel 10)
    - 40. Wien effect in simple strong electrolytes (Box 15, Folder 41, Reel 10)
    - 41. The relaxation effects in mixed strong electrolytes (Box 15, Folder 42, Reel 10)
    - 42. Conductance of unassociated electrolytes (Box 15, Folder 43, Reel 10)
    - 43. The kinetic term in electrolytic conductance (Box 15, Folder 44, Reel 10)
    - 44. Low temperature fluctuations (Box 15, Folder 45, Reel 10)
    - 45. Many-electron wave function (Box 15, Folder 46, Reel 10)
    - 46. Surface specific heat of an isotropic solid at low temperatures (Box 15, Folder 47, Reel 10)
    - 47. Proton magnetic resonance spectrum of propane (Box 15, Folder 48, Reel 10)
    - 48. Electrical properties of ice (Box 15, Folder 49, Reel 10)
    - 49. Magnetic flux through a superconducting ring (Box 15, Folder 50, Reel 10)
    - 50. Thermodynamic potentials of symmetrical electrolytes (Box 15, Folder 51, Reel 10)
    - 51. The conductance of symmetrical electrolytes. I. Potential of total force (Box 15, Folder 52, Reel 10)
    - 52. The electrical properties of ice (Box 15, Folder 53, Reel 10)
    - 53. The electrical properties of ice (Box 15, Folder 54, Reel 10)
    - 54. The conductance of symmetrical electrolytes. II. The relaxation field (Box 15, Folder 55, Reel 10)
    - 55. The conductance of symmetrical electrolytes. III. Electrophoresis (Box 15, Folder 56, Reel 10)
    - 56. Mechanism for self-diffusion in ice (Box 15, Folder 57, Reel 10)
    - 57. Helium II (Box 15, Folder 58, Reel 10)
    - 58. A correction to the Poisson-Boltzmann equation for unsymmetrical electrolytes (Box 15, Folder 59, Reel 10)
    - 59. The conductance of symmetrical electrolytes. IV. Hydrodynamic and osmotic terms in the relaxation field (Box 15, Folder 60, Reel 10)
    - 60. Electrons in liquids (Box 15, Folder 61, Reel 10)
    - 61. Electrons in metals (Box 15, Folder 62, Reel 10)
    - 62. Zur Theorie des Wieneffekts in schwachen Elektrolyten (Box 15, Folder 63, Reel 10)
    - 63. The conductance of symmetrical electrolytes. V. The conductance equation (Box 15, Folder 64, Reel 10)
    - 64. Integrals in the theory of electron correlations (Box 15, Folder 65, Reel 10)
    - 65. Ferroelectricity of ice? (Box 15, Folder 66, Reel 10)
    - 66. Thermodynamics and some molecular aspects of biology (Box 15, Folder 67, Reel 10)
    - 70. Protonic semiconductors (Box 15, Folder 71, Reel 10)
    - 67. Relaxation effects in associating electrolytes (Box 15, Folder 68, Reel 10)
    - 68. The motion of ions: principles and concepts (Box 15, Folder 69, Reel 10)
    - 69. Diffusion and relaxation phenomena in ice (Box 15, Folder 70, Reel 10)
    - 71. Possible mechanisms of ion transit (Box 15, Folder 72, Reel 10)
    - 72. The Ising model in two dimensions (Box 15, Folder 73, Reel 10)
    - 73. Life in the early days (Box 15, Folder 74, Reel 10)
    - 74. The effect of wall charge on the capillary rise of electrolytes (Box 15, Folder 75, Reel 10)
    - 75. Surface specific heat of crystals (Box 15, Folder 76, Reel 10)
    - 76. Interpretation of kinetic and equilibrium properties (of water) (Box 15, Folder 77, Reel 10)
    - 79. Electrons and vortex lines in He II, I. Brownian motion theory of capture and escape (Box 15, Folder 78, Reel 10)
    - 80. Electrons and vortex lines in He II, II. Theoretical analysis of capture and release experiments (Box 15, Folder 79, Reel 10)
    - "Zur Statistik Irreversibler Prozesse" (with S. Machlup), Phys. Verhdlg. 3(1952), 84 (Box 15, Folder 80, Reel 10)
    - "Introductory Lecture," in E. Whalley et al., eds., Physics and Chemistry of Ice (1973) (Box 15, Folder 81, Reel 10)
    - Posthumous joint publications (Box 15, Folder 82, Reel 10)
  - Pre-Publication Material
    - 6-7. Reciprocal relations in irreversible processes: edited Tss (Box 16, Folder 83, Reel 10)
    - 10. Theories of concentrated electrolytes
      See: box 5, folder 15
    - 12. Deviations from Ohm's law in weak electrolytes: figures (Box 16, Folder 84, Reel 10)
    - 13. Solutions of the Mathieu equation of period 4. and certain related functions: letter from prospective publisher (Box 16, Folder 85, Reel 10)
    - 16. Electrostatic interaction of molecules: Ts (Box 16, Folder 86, Reel 10)
    - 17. On the theory of isotope separation by thermal diffusion
      See: box 9, folder 81 See: box 9, folder 93
    - 21. Anisotropic solutions of colloids
    - 22. Crystal statistics. I
    - 26. Transition points: Ts edited for printer (Box 16, Folder 87, Reel 10)
    - 28. Effects of shape on the interaction of colloidal particles: Ms (Box 16, Folder 88, Reel 10)
    - 29. Crystal statistics. III
      See: box 9, folders 96-97
    - 30. Statistical hydrodynamics: Ts (Box 16, Folder 89, Reel 10)
      See: box 18, folder 1
    - 33. General theory for the Gouy diffusion method
      See: box 9, folder 87
    - 34. Fluctuations and irreversible processes: Ts (Box 16, Folder 90, Reel 10)
    - 35. Fluctuations and irreversible process. II: Ts (Box 16, Folder 91, Reel 10)
    - 41. The relaxation effects in mixed strong electrolytes: notes, Ts (Box 16, Folder 92, Reel 10)
      See: box 5, folder 17 See: box 6, folder 36
    - 46. Surface specific heat of an isotopic solid at low temperatures: editorial correspondence, partial Ts, figures (Box 16, Folder 93, Reel 11)
    - 49. Magnetic flux through a superconducting ring: Ts (Box 16, Folder 94, Reel 11)
    - 51. Conductance of symmetrical electrolytes. I. Potential of total force: notes (Box 16, Folder 95, Reel 11)
      See: box 5, folder 16
    - 53. The electrical properties of ice: figures (Box 16, Folder 96, Reel 11)
    - 55. The conductance of symmetrical electrolytes. III. Electrophoresis
    - 57. Helium II
      See: box 10, folder 109 See: box 18, folder 2
    - 58. A correction to the Poisson-Boltzmann equation for unsymmetrical electrolytes
    - 62. Zur Theorie des Wieneffekts in schwachen Electrolyten: Ms, Ts (Box 16, Folder 97, Reel 11)
    - 60. Electrons in liquids: Ts (copy) (Box 16, Folder 98, Reel 11)
    - 61. Electrons in metals: Ts (Box 16, Folder 99, Reel 11)
    - 65. Integrals in the theory of electron correlations
      See: box 18, folder 8
    - 66. Thermodynamics and some molecular aspects of biology: partial Ms, Ts (Box 16, Folder 100, Reel 11)
    - 70. Protonic semiconductors: edited preprint, also Ts abstract in German? (Box 16, Folder 101, Reel 11)
      See: box 18, folders 10
    - 71. Possible mechanisms of ion transit: partial Ms, Ts (copy) (Box 16, Folder 102, Reel 11)
    - 72. The Ising model in two dimensions: Ts (copy) (Box 16, Folder 103, Reel 11)
      See: box 18, folder 12
    - 73. Life in the early days: Ts, list of recipients (Box 16, Folder 104, Reel 11)
    - 75. Surface specific heat of crystals: Ts, letters from co-author T.Y. Moon (Box 16, Folder 105, Reel 11)
    - 76. Interpretation of kinetic and equilibrium properties: Ts (copy) (Box 16, Folder 106, Reel 11)
    - 77. Asymptotic forms for luminescent intensity due to donor-acceptor pair recombinations: edited Ts (copy) (Box 16, Folder 107, Reel 11)
    - 78. Hopping of ions in ice: Ts (copy), preprint (Box 16, Folder 108, Reel 11)
    - 78. Hopping of ions in ice: Ts and Ts (copy) drafts (Box 17, Folder 109, Reel 11)
    - 79. Electrons and vortex lines in He II, I: Brownian motion theory of capture and escape: Ts (copy) (Box 17, Folder 110, Reel 11)
    - 80. Electrons and vortex lines in He II, II: theoretical analysis of capture and release experiments: Ts (copy) (Box 17, Folder 111, Reel 11)
    - 82. The generalized conductance equation: partial Ms, Ts (copy), correspondence with co-author M.S. Chen (Box 17, Folder 112, Reel 11)
    - "Introductory Lecture," in E. Whalley et. al., eds., Physics and Chemistry of Ice (1973): Ts (Box 17, Folder 113, Reel 11)
    - "Partial Free Energies of Ions" (unpublished): comments of referees, 1928 (Box 17, Folder 114, Reel 11)
    - "Ion Passages in Lipid Bilayers": Ts (Box 17, Folder 115, Reel 11)
    - "Vortex Fluctuations and the Negative Ion Trapping Lifetime: Quantum Theory of the Vortex 'Core" (with J. McCauley, Jr.): Ts (copy) (Box 17, Folder 116, Reel 11)
    - "Primordial Membranes": MS (Box 17, Folder 117, Reel 11)
    - "Dielectric Dispersion and Dielectric Friction in Electrolyte Solutions. I" (with J. Hubbard): partial Ts, ALS (copy) to R. Zwanzig, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 118, Reel 11)
    - "Quantization of Magnetic Flux": Ts abstract (Box 17, Folder 119, Reel 11)
    - "The Theory of the Wien Effect for Binary Electrolytes" (with W.S. Wilson): Ts, ca. 1936 (Box 17, Folder 120, Reel 11)
    - "Crystal Statistics. IV. Long Range Order in a Binary Crystal" (with B. Kaufman): Ts, TL (copy), Onsager to B. Kaufman, 1950 (Box 17, Folder 121, Reel 11)
    - Zur Statistik Irreversibler Vorgänge (with S. Machlup): correspondence, 1952, edited proof (Box 17, Folder 122, Reel 11)
    - Essay on the origin of life: Ms in german (Box 17, Folder 123, Reel 11)
    - Essays on electrolytes: Ts, Ts abstract ("The material or its equivalent has been published"-Raymond M. Fuoss) (Box 17, Folder 124, Reel 11)
    - Review of J. Frenkel, The Kinetic Theory of Liquids: Ts (Box 17, Folder 125, Reel 11)
    - Review of "Lectures on Nuclear Physics at Zurich, May 1931," Physik. Z. 32 (1931): Ts (Box 17, Folder 126, Reel 11)
    - "Asymptotic Forms for Luminescent Intensity Due to Donor-Acceptor Pair Recombination" (with A.M. Stewart)
      See: box 6, folder 45
  - Lecture Series
    - "Methods of Statistical Mechanics," 1948 (Box 17, Folder 127, Reel 11)
    - "Kinetic Theory and Statistical Mechanics," compiled by Don E. Harrison, Jr., 1952 (Box 17, Folder 128, Reel 11)
    - "Lectures on Protonic Semiconductors," Center for Theoretical Studies, University of Miami, CTS-LN-68-2, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 129, Reel 11)
- CONFERENCES, 1935-1977; Series IV; 1.5 linear feet (4 boxes)
  This series has two sections, Onsager Text and No Onsager Text, each of which is in chronological order. The folder headings in Onsager Text specify the names and dates of the conferences and the types of Onsager texts included in the papers, but they do not describe whatever other kinds of material may be present. The numbers in parentheses after the specifications of certain texts (e.g., "(no. 30)" in folder 1) correspond to the numbering of Onsager publications in the Royal Society bibliography, as shown in Series III, folders 3-79. The folder list for No Onsager Text is a simple sequence of dates, with no naming of the conferences and no description of the papers.
  - Onsager Text
    - International Symposium on Statistical Mechanics: transcript, edited proofs (no. 30), 1949 May 17-20 (Box 18, Folder 1, Reel 12)
    - Conference on Irreversible Processes: bibliographic note, 1955 March 31-April 2 (Box 18, Folder 2, Reel 12)
    - Symposium on the Many-Body Problem: edited transcript, proof (no. 57), 1957 January 28-29 (Box 18, Folder 3, Reel 12)
    - Symposium on the Structure of Electrolytic Solutions: transcript, 1957 May 12-16 (Box 18, Folder 3, Reel 12)
    - International Symposium on Electrolytes: notes, abstract, report to the funding agency, 1959 June 4-8 (Box 18, Folder 4, Reel 12)
    - Conference on Basic Mechanisms in the Radiation Chemistry of Aqueous Media: program notes, transcript, 1963 May 8-10 (Box 18, Folder 5, Reel 12)
    - Gibbs Lecture, American Mathematical Society: abstract, transparencies, 1964 January 24 (Box 18, Folder 6, Reel 12)
    - Symposium on Non-Equilibrium Thermodynamics and Variational Techniques and Stability: program notes, 1965 May 17-19 (Box 18, Folder 7, Reel 12)
    - Symposium on Ferroelectricity: post-symposium text (no. 65), 1966 September (Box 18, Folder 8, Reel 12)
    - San Francisco Conference on Metal-Nonmetal Transition: transcript, 1968 pre-April 8 (Box 18, Folder 9, Reel 12)
    - International Symposium on Physics of Ice: drafts (no. 70), 1968 September 9-14 (Box 18, Folder 10, Reel 12)
    - University of Texas, Advanced School of Statistical Mechanics and Thermodynamics: notes on liquid ammonia, 1969 March 17-28 (Box 18, Folder 11, Reel 12)
    - Battelle Colloquium on Critical Phenomena: draft, edited proof (no. 72), 1970 September 7-12 (Box 18, Folder 12, Reel 12)
    - H.S. Harned Memorial Symposium: abstract, 1970 September 14-15 (Box 18, Folder 13, Reel 12)
    - Cinquième Conférence Internationale "de la Physique Théorique à la Biologie": notes, transcript, 1973 May 28-June 2 (Box 19, Folder 14, Reel 12)
    - American Chemical Society, Florida Section: abstract, 1975 May 8-10 (Box 19, Folder 15, Reel 12)
    - Sixième Conférence Internationale "de la Biologie": critique of tentative program, 1975 June 16-21 (Box 19, Folder 16, Reel 12)
    - College Park Colloquia on Chemical Evolution, Chemical Evolution of the Early Precambrian: notes, transcript, 1975 October 29-November 1 (Box 19, Folder 17, Reel 12)
    - Académie Internationale d'Histoire des Sciences, 1977 June 20-25 (Box 19, Folder 18, Reel 12)
    - Faraday Division of the Chemical Society, General Discussion on "Ion-Ion and Ion-Solvent Interactions": proposal, 1977 September 13-15 (Box 19, Folder 19, Reel 12)
  - No Onsager Text
    - 1935, 1946-1953, 1957-1967, 1968 September, 1968 December, 1969 May-December, 1970 April-Jul, 1970 September-December, [1970 December-1971 January?], 1971 January-April, 1971 June-December, 1972 January-May (Box 20, Folder 20-39, Reel 12)
    - 1972 June-December, 1973 January-December, 1974 January-May, 1974 July-December, 1975 March-November, 1975 December-1976 January, 1976 March-Sep, 1976 November-1977 June, undated (Box 21, Folder 40-58, Reel 12)
- PROJECTS & INSTITUTIONS, 1946-1976; Series V; 1.5 linear feet (4 boxes)
  This series has twelve sections in alphabetical order: Air Force Office of Scientific Research, Army Research Office, Atomic Energy Commission, Fulbright Scholarship, Gauss Professorship, Lorentz Professorship, National Institutes of Health, National Science Foundation, Neurosciences Research Program, Office of Naval Research, University of Miami Center for Theoretical Studies, and Yale University. In general, the papers in each section are arranged by type.
  - Air Force Office of Scientific Research
    - Correspondence and proposals, 1971 (Box 22, Folder 1, Reel 13)
    - Correspondence and report, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 2, Reel 13)
    - Army Research Office: correspondence and report, 1974, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 3, Reel 13)
  - Atomic Energy Commission
    - Contracts and related correspondence, 1961-1969 (Box 22, Folder 4, Reel 13)